pesi.com 2019-05-11

# Privacy Policy

PESI has created this Privacy Policy to demonstrate our firm commitment to your privacy. We highly value the trust and confidence our customers have developed in PESI. In short, our mission is to protect your data and will do everything we can, not to jeopardize our relationship with you. 

We use your data to provide you with the best customer experience. By continuing to use our website, or to order products or services from us, you agree to the terms set forth in this Privacy Policy. To illustrate our intent, the following discloses our information collection, utilization, and protection practices. 

####  The type of information we collect 

As part of administering our sites, our servers log IP address and corresponding information (such as operating system, browser version, etc.) which allows us to monitor the amount of traffic to our server as well as the accessibility of our site to our customers. 

Our e-commerce software requires visitors to accept a cookie when browsing or shopping. The cookie is merely used to facilitate your navigation through our site as you select items and place them in your shopping cart. This cookie is not used for any reason after the session in which it was issued. Rather, a new cookie is issued upon subsequent visits. By continuing to use our site & services you are consenting to the use of cookies as described in this Privacy Policy. 

Third party service providers (like CE21, Google, Facebook, etc.), may provide information about you when you link, connect, or login to your account with the third-party provider. The information varies and is controlled by that service provider or as authorized by you via your privacy settings at that service provider. 

Although you may request to be added to our house file at any time, placement of an order or registration will add you and your contact information automatically, such as name and address, phone number and email address. We will use this information to make any necessary clarifications to your order/registration, to confirm receipt of payment, and to inform you of any significant changes in product ship date, seminar outline or seminar location that may affect you. You may also receive further communication regarding comparable products and upcoming seminars and/or communications from relevant third parties. Since our products and services are intended for professionals, we do not intend to collect personal information from, or market to, anyone under the legal purchase age. If we are notified, or if we believe you are under the legal purchasing age, we will remove your personal information from our records. 

####  How we use your information 

We may use and process your information where you have consented for us to do so, including to contact you about relevant offers and resources from the best professionals in the world or if you voluntarily sign up to receive any of our products or services. 

Where we have supplied you with any product or service, we may use your information to contact you if there are any changes to those products or services, such as a date change or a change in continuing education. It is in your best interest for us to use your information in this way to continue to provide you a positive customer experience. 

We may use and process your information where it is necessary for us to pursue our legitimate interests as a business, or that of a third party, for the following purposes: for analysis with our marketing strategy, to correspond or communicate with you, for prevention of fraud and other criminal activities, to comply with government requirements and requests, to comply with a request from you in connection with the exercise of your rights, to improve service to customers through recordings of calls to our customer service department, to manage requests to our customer service help desk emails, for the establishment and defense of our legal rights, and to enhance and personalize your customer experience. 

Although we do not sell e-mail addresses or phone numbers, we may, upon occasion, sell the names and physical addresses from our house file to an agency of an appropriate and related purpose. By supplying your contact information and allowing yourself to be added to our house list, it is assumed that you agree to this practice unless you specifically indicate otherwise. 

We may disclose your information to our third party service providers, agents, subcontractors and other organizations for the purposes of providing services to us or directly to you on our behalf. Such third parties may include logistics or delivery companies, cloud service providers (such as hosting and email management), marketing agencies and administrative services. 

When we use third party service providers, we only disclose to them any information that is necessary for them to provide their service and we have a contract in place that requires them to keep your information secure and not to use it other than in accordance with our specific instructions. 

We may obtain certain non-precise location information about you based on information we obtain from your IP address, or with your consent, your mobile device. We may use this information to improve and customize the services we offer, for example event listings or relevant offers. We use IP addresses to analyze trends, track access and aggregate broad demographic and search information. 

####  Information Protection 

We use Transport Layer Security (TLS) encryption to protect your personal and credit card information when placing orders and registering for events via our web site. TLS is the standard Internet encryption technology, which is a highly sophisticated method of scrambling data as it travels from your computer to our website's servers. All credit card information is forwarded through the encrypted TLS layer to our credit card transaction processor. 

All the information you provide to us may be stored either in the United Kingdom, United States, Australia, or in the case of third-party cloud service providers, in locations that provide the best availability and service to our customers. Your data will be stored and kept safe for such periods as we deem necessary - taking into account the purpose for which it was collected - to comply with our legal obligations, support our business operations and to continue providing exceptional customer service. 

If at any time you wish to update or remove certain information you have provided to us or you wish to be removed entirely from our house file, please contact us and specify the appropriate changes. If you would like to remain on our house list but would like to discontinue a specific form of communication (i.e. e-mail, mail or third-party offers), please contact us and let us know what type of communication you would no longer like to receive. Should you choose, you may update your preferences at any time. 

You may change or correct your account information at any time by logging into your account and changing the settings, or by contacting our Customer Service department. Depending on your country of origin, you may have additional rights with respect to your information you provided to us, such as the right to obtain a copy of your information you provided to us and the right to have your information deleted, except for information we are legally required to retain. You have the choice to withdraw your consent in how we use and store your personal information at any time. 

####  Questions? 

If you have any questions about this policy, please contact us. Please mention this Privacy Policy in your inquiry to help us expedite your request. Please note: We reserve the right to update this Privacy Policy at any time in order to meet new releases of privacy regulations. 

####  Last Updated 

May 24, 2018
